<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Nate Winn</title>
 <link href="http://natewinn.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://natewinn.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-05-10T13:25:41-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://natewinn.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Nate Winn</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Halfway There</title>
   <link href="http://natewinn.com/2014/05/10/halfway-there/"/>
   <updated>2014-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://natewinn.com/2014/05/10/halfway-there</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My son, Owen, will be 9 months old tomorrow. &lt;em&gt;I can&amp;#39;t believe how fast the time has gone by&lt;/em&gt;! On days this, I like to look through the pictures my wife and I have taken of him and take just a few moments to reminisce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without fail, I say to my wife, &amp;quot;I can&amp;#39;t believe how much he has grown!&amp;quot; In fact, I always remind her of the picture I took when she put him in his carseat for the the very first time. His newborn clothes were so big on him and he nearly disappeared into his carseat. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s so apparent by looking back to his first few days of life to see how much he has grown. He now sleeps through the night, crawls, interacts with us, and climbs on things (yes, he climbed up there all by himself in that picture below). My son&amp;#39;s growth or &amp;quot;progress&amp;quot; is &lt;em&gt;so easy to overlook on a daily basis&lt;/em&gt;. My progress at The Iron Yard is no different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2014-05-10-owen-on-nightstand.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Owen on the Nightstand&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Owen perched on his favorite spot&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Overlooking Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The daily grind is taxing and it seems that our cohort is making slow progress. But, when you take a step back and look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/natewinn/9912926&quot;&gt;first gist&lt;/a&gt; we posted on GitHub, you can definitely see it. &lt;em&gt;Real, genuine progress&lt;/em&gt;! Don&amp;#39;t get me wrong, in the world of RubyOnRails I&amp;#39;m still an infant crawling around on the floor. But I&amp;#39;m definately not a newborn any longer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six weeks ago today, I boarded an airplane to leave my family knowing next to nothing about code. Yesterday, I pushed a web app to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/natewinn/remember&quot;&gt;GitHub Repo&lt;/a&gt; where users can upload photos and add tags and comments. And, no, I didn&amp;#39;t know what a &amp;quot;GitHub Repo&amp;quot; was 6 weeks ago. Looking back, today, at &amp;quot;half-time,&amp;quot; &lt;em&gt;it is amazing to see the progress&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When setting out to achieve a goal, no matter how big or small, I challenge you to take a step back on &lt;strong&gt;milestone days&lt;/strong&gt; and recall the progress you made. Not to pat yourself on the back for the steps that you&amp;#39;ve made, but to motivate you to accomplish even more in the days ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>In One Year's Time</title>
   <link href="http://natewinn.com/2014/04/09/in-one-years-time/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://natewinn.com/2014/04/09/in-one-years-time</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Exactly one year ago today, I created an account at &lt;a href=&quot;http://devbootcamp.com/&quot;&gt;Dev Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; and began to fill out an applicaiton in hopes to join an upcoming cohort. But, that very same night, I began to reason to myself why I would never be able to attend. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Excuses, Excuses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I had &lt;em&gt;plenty of excuses&lt;/em&gt;. In just three months, my wife and I were expecting our first child, I had no where near the money I needed for entry, and then there was the small detail of supporting my family without any income for three months! My aspirations of attending a coding bootcamp became a distant memory. I was twenty-nine years-old and accepted the fact that my time to do work that truly excited me had past. I came to accept it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after the first of the year, I was casually browsing through Twitter and noticed &lt;a href=&quot;http://john.do/&quot;&gt;John Saddington&lt;/a&gt;, whom I have been following for years, mention &lt;a href=&quot;http://theironyard.com/&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly googled &amp;quot;The Iron Yard&amp;quot;  and my curiousity was instantly peaked. I immediately emailed John, and it just so happened that he was going to be in San Francisco the very next day to speak at a conference. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;My Year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While grabbing sushi that very next evening, John told me just a handful of the amazing stories of people in similar situations that had attended The Iron Yard. In just a 3-month period of time, people were completely changing the course of their life. Just before I hopped into my car to drive home from the city that evening, John tweeted this . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make this the year. Don’t let it go to waste.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; John Saddington (@saddington) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/saddington/statuses/428403179722506240&quot;&gt;January 29, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night, I decided this &lt;em&gt;was going to be my year&lt;/em&gt;! Last Sunday, I moved sight unseen across the country from the Silicon Valley to Atlanta to become a coder. Today, exactly one year from the day I registered at Dev Bootcamp, I&amp;#39;m writing this post from inside &lt;a href=&quot;http://atlantatechvillage.com/&quot;&gt;Atlanta Tech Village&lt;/a&gt;, the amazing facility where The Iron Yard - Atlanta is located. Though only one-week into the Rails dev cohort, I&amp;#39;ve already been challenged, stretched, and pushed more in this short period than I ever have in my entire life. It has been an amazing ride so far and I can&amp;#39;t wait to see what lies in store. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
